二 一 六 四 二 零
Two one six four two zero
一 九 八 九
one nine eight nine.
小姑娘 那就是π的小数点后一千位
And that, little lady, is pi to a thousand places.
我本来能说 真不该问你
I'd say I'm sorry I asked,
可是我没问
except I didn't.
哦 你看 这期科学美国人
Oh, look, it's the Scientific American
报道了Leonard和我写的那篇论文
that covered the paper Leonard and I wrote.
哦 让我看看
Oh, let me see.
我对接受采访的态度很复杂
I have mixed feelings about doing interviews.
我喜欢自己说话
I like the part where I talk.
但是我不喜欢听别人说话
I do not like the part where the other man talks.
Sheldon 这篇文章一点都没有提到Leonard
Sheldon, this article doesn't mention Leonard at all.
这不可能吧
Well, that can't be right.
它上面只写了"Cooper博士和他的团队"
It only refers to "Dr. Cooper and his team."
你谈到过他吗?
Did you even talk about him?
我只是回答了几个关于这个理论的问题
All I did was answer a few questions about the theory.
我还感谢了科学美国人
And then expressed my gratitude that Scientific American
没有寄来那些臭臭的香水卡片
doesn't include any of those smelly perfume cards.
Leonard真可怜
Poor Leonard.
为什么? 他想出来的理论
Why? The theory he came up with
被科学美国人报道了
just got mentioned in Scientific American.
他应该很兴奋啊
He ought to be thrilled.
他也许不会
He might not be.
哦 也许你说的对
Oh, maybe you're right.
他是有点笨笨的
He is kind of a lump.
你自己想想看
Think about it.
如果他们说你是Leonard的团队里的一员
How would you feel if you were referred to
你会怎么想?
as part of Leonard's team?
哦 我会非常生气的
Oh, I'd be incensed.
那你明白我想说什么了吗?
So you see what I'm getting at?
吱吱叫的轮子有油加?
Squeaky wheel gets the grease?
不是
No.
这山望着那山高?
Grass is always greener?
再试试
Try again.
啊 我不知道... 我们都是树精格鲁特?
Well, I don't know... we're all Groot?
告诉我吧
Just tell me.
Leonard和你对这份论文的贡献一样大
Leonard is as much a part of this paper
而他被忽视了
as you are, and he was overlooked.
他会很难过的
He's going to feel bad.
但这不是我的错啊
But it wasn't my fault.
我又没有把他排除出去
I didn't exclude him.
这篇文章也不是我写的
And I didn't write the article.
你还记得你在迪士尼乐园那次 他们没有选你
Remember that time you didn't get picked to pull the sword out
去拔石中剑 而是挑了另外一个小孩吗?
of the stone at Disneyland and they let that other kid do it?
哦 那小屁孩!
Oh, that kid!
Leonard真可怜
Poor Leonard.
是啊
Exactly.
我得说一句 选那小孩太不明智了
For the record, that kid was a terrible choice.
如果你的油条掉到地上了你就要哭
If you cry when you drop your churro,
那你完全没有统治英格兰的能耐
you do not have what it takes to rule England.
* 宇宙一度又烫又稠密 *
* Our whole universe was in a hot, dense state *
* 140亿年前终于爆了炸... 等着瞧! *
* Then nearly 14 billion years ago expansion started... Wait! *
* 地球开始降温 *
* The Earth began to cool *
* 自养生物来起哄 穴居人发明工具 *
* The autotrophs began to drool, Neanderthals developed tools *
* 我们建长城 我们建金字塔 *
* We built the Wall We built the pyramids *
* 数学 自然科学 历史 揭开神秘 *
* Math, Science, History, unraveling the mystery *
* 一切由大爆炸开始 *
* That all started with a big bang *
生活大爆炸 第八季18集
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 酥酥阿姨
翻译: 黄字君 奥利奥 夏至未寒
校对: UU养了只狐狸叫查理
谢谢你帮我们整理我妈妈的东西
Thanks for helping us sort through all my mom's stuff.
不用谢
Of course.
我知道 去翻看
I know what it's like
所爱之人的遗物 是什么样的感受
having to go through a loved one's possessions.
我的叔叔崇拜的是奎师那
My uncle was a worshipper of Krishna.
但他去世以后 你知道我们发现什么了吗?
But after he died, you know what we found?
一个湿婆的塑像
A statue of Shiva.
虽然不是什么血雨腥风的帮派对头
It may not be Crips and Bloods, okay?
但在印度 这也算是个事
But in India, it's a thing.
呃 你在就好
Well, it'll be good that you're there.
Howard难以决定
Howard's been having trouble deciding
什么要留下来什么要丢掉
what to keep and what to let go.
啊 这是很难
Well, it's hard.
妈妈的很多东西都会勾起一些快乐的回忆
A lot of Ma's stuff brings back fond memories.
所以你才不愿意丢掉
Is that why you couldn't get rid of
她那个装满番茄酱的抽屉吗?
her drawer full of ketchup packets?
是啊 这让我记起来 我们在外面吃饭的时候 她对我说
Yes. It reminds me of us eating out and her saying,
"快 没人看着 多拿点番茄酱放你口袋里"
"Quick, nobody's looking, fill your pockets with ketchup"
Leonard啊?
Leonard?
你有没有注意过
Have you ever noticed that
有线电视的账单上只有我的名字?
only my name is on the cable bill?
是的
Yeah.
好的 好的
Good, good.
电费单上只有你的名字
And your name is on the electric bill
而没有我的
and mine isn't.
而且我对这件事没什么意见
And I'm okay with that.
其实 电费单上写的是你的名字
Actually, your name is on the electric bill.
哦 对哦
Oh, right.
真是个灾难
This is a disaster.
我完全不知道你在讲什么 我还同意你的说法
I don't even know what you're talking about and I agree.
好吧 有件事我要告诉你
Okay, I have to tell you something,
但你会不高兴的
but you're not going to like it.
怎么了?
What's going on?
科学美国人上发表了一篇
An article was just published
关于我们理论的文章
in Scientific American about our theory.
他们很讨厌它吗?
Did they hate it?
不 不 他们爱死它了
No. No, they loved it.
他们 呃 说了一大堆好话
They, uh, couldn't say enough nice things about it.
那有什么问题吗?
So what's the problem?
你知道我们的省钱一族...
You know how the Penny Saver only has my name...
Sheldon啊!
Sheldon!
那篇文章里他们没有提到你
They didn't mention you in the article.
只提到了我
Only me.
真的?
Really?
是啊
I know.
这不公平
It's not fair.
放下你的怒火 兄弟
Let the anger go, buddy.
你...
You just...
放松所有的肌肉
you relax all your muscles.
除了你的耻尾肌和肛管括约肌
Except for your pubococcygeus and anal sphincter.
那两个要收紧了
Let's keep those tight.
呃 不... 你不需要这样的
Uh, that... that's not necessary.
其实需要... 他们是帮你憋尿憋屎用的
It is... they're what hold back the urine and the feces.
听着 也许... 也许你不该读
Look, maybe... maybe you shouldn't read it.
你只会感觉更糟糕
It'll only make you feel worse.
"Cooper和他的团队"?
"Cooper and his team"?
你要知道这件事和我完全没关系
You should know I had nothing to do with that.
呃...
Uh...
至少他们在讨论这个理论
at least they're talking about the theory.
我是说 这个最重要
I mean, that's what's important.
你说的对
You know, you're right.
是啊 就像斯坦·李和史蒂夫·迪特科
Yeah. You know, it's like when Stan Lee and Steve Ditko
一起创作了蜘蛛侠
created Spider-Man.
功劳全被斯坦·李占了
Stan Lee may get all the credit,
但是史蒂夫·迪特科知道他也一样重要
but Steve Ditko knows he was just as important.
虽然斯坦·李可以在所有的漫威电影里出镜
Even though Stan Lee gets to be in all the Marvel movies.
而且... 而且他还很有钱
And... and he's far richer.
而且他是个家喻户晓的人了 对吧?
And he's a household name, you know?
但是 你说迪斯科
Whereas, you know, you say Ditko,
听上去感觉是个公司的名字
and that sounds like a company that makes Dits.
你这是帮倒忙
That's not helping.
好吧 我能再多举几个例子的
Well, I'd give more examples,
但是像你这样被遗落的人 实在太难想起来还有谁了
but, well, everyone in your position's so forgettable.
Stuart 我们来了
Stuart, we're here.
你让他继续住在你妈妈的屋子真好
It's nice of you to let him keep staying at your mom's house.
是啊 我本来想把他丢到路边去的
Yeah, well, I tried putting him out on the curb,
但是没有人愿意收留他
but nobody took him.
嘿
Hey.
跟你说一下 这里停电了
Just so you know, the power's out.
怎么了?
What happened?
我打电话问了 他们说一个变压器爆炸了
I called, they said a transformer blew.
整个街区都停电了
It's the whole block.
应该明天就修好了
Should be fixed by tomorrow.
等等 什么时候停电的?
Wait, when did it go out?
半夜的时候
In the middle of the night.
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
Howie 怎么了?
Howie, what's wrong?
全都解冻了
It's all defrosting.
没事的 只是食物而已
It's okay. It's just food.
这不只是食物
It's not just food.
这是我妈做的唯一剩下的食物
This is the last food my mother ever made.
这是她仅剩的牛胸肉
This is her last brisket.
这是她仅剩的烘肉卷
This is her last meatloaf.
这是她仅剩的...
This is her last...
我看不出这是什么 但是...
I have no idea what this is, but...
这是仅剩的了
it's the last one.
一切还好吗?
Everything okay?
不好
No.
老妈做的所有食物都要变质了
All Ma's food is gonna be ruined.
我们为什么不拿回家 放进咱们的冰箱里?
Well, why don't we take it home and put it in our freezer?
你不会想这么做的
You don't want to do that.
再冰冻不仅会使它脱水
Refreezing not only removes moisture,
更会在肉纤维表面形成冰晶
but it creates ice crystals in the fibers of the meat
进而影响口感和质地
that can compromise its taste and texture.
怎么了? 我看到说教的机会
What? I saw a teachable moment.
就显摆了些烹饪学问
I dropped some culinary science.
我们该怎么办呢?
What should we do?
我来告诉你该怎么办
I'll tell you exactly what we're gonna do.
把它吃了
We're gonna eat it.
这里差不不多有二十磅的食物
There's, like, 20 pounds of food in there.
你只说过
All you said
我要处理掉它们
was I had to get rid of things.
又没说不能让它们先通过我的肠道
You didn't say they couldn't pass through my colon first.
哎Howie...
Howie...
好吧
Okay.
那这样吧?
Then how about this?
我们请大家过来吃晚饭
Let's invite everyone over to dinner.
就当是老妈做的最后一顿饭
It'll be like Ma's feeding us one last time.
我喜欢这主意
I love that.
我也是
Me, too.
快看 我们有足够的番茄酱
Oh, look, we've got enough ketchup
来蘸满所有食物
to cover every ounce of it.
我说 到底有谁读"科学美国人"杂志?
I mean, who even reads Scientific American?
这其实挺重要的
It's kind of a big deal.
如果真有这么重要 为什么封面明星
If it's such a big deal, how come the biggest celebrity
最大牌的就是一个分子了?
they could get for the cover is a molecule?
我们可以别谈这个了吗?
Can we please just stop talking about it?
对不起 我能做什么呢?
I'm sorry. What can I do?
什么也不用 我没事
Nothing, I'm fine.
不不 我要让你振作起来
No, no. I'm gonna cheer you up.
要开始了
Here we go.
打算做什么呢?
What are we doing?
- 我要带你购物  - 哦
- I am taking you shopping.  - Oh.
我的宝贝不开心 我要哄他高兴
My baby is sad, and I'm gonna make him happy again.
听着 我知道购物让你高兴
Look, I know shopping cheers you up,
但我真不喜欢这个
but it's just not really my thing.
那这架由iPad控制的
Well, what about this helicopter
直升机如何呢?
you control with an iPad?
配备摄像头吗?
Does it have a camera in it?
它有配备摄像头哟
It does have a camera in it.
宝贝在听
Baby's listening.
喂Leonard?
Leonard?
喂Leonard? Leonard?
Leonard? Leonard?
怎么了?
What?
我跟杂志的记者谈过了
I spoke to the reporter at the magazine.
情况怎样? 有说这是我的主意了吗?
What happened? Did you tell him it was my idea?
我说了
I did.
谢谢你 他怎么说?
Thank you. What did he say?
他说杂志编撰要求文章
He said they made the editorial decision
只引用首席科学家
to only cite the lead scientist.
他怎么会以为你是首席科学家?
Why did he think you're the lead scientist?
这可是我的主意!
It was my idea!
要知道 多付四块钱的话
You know, for an extra four bucks,
这东西明天就能寄到
I can have this thing here tomorrow.
我知道这是你的主意
Well, I know it was your idea,
但那个记者说他关注我的研究很久了
but the reporter said he's been following my work for a while,
他们在杂志里引用我们的论文
and the only reason they even mentioned it in the magazine
只因为里面有我的名字
is 'cause my name is on it.
你知道吗? 我付了 四块钱算什么?
You know what? I did it. What's four bucks?
如果你是在让我好受点
If you're trying to make me feel better,
这么做没用
it's not working.
那... 要是我告诉你
Well... then what if I told you
我把你名字加进了有线电视账单呢?
that I added your name to the cable bill?
- 没用  - 哦
- No.  - Oh.
这样也好 他们让我候机了
That's just as well. They had me on hold
整整20分钟 然后我就挂了 我...
for 20 minutes and I hung up. I...
喂Leonard? Leonard?
Leonard? Leonard?
喂Leonard?
Leonard?
还有 Wolowitz请大家去吃晚饭 所以...
Also, Wolowitz invited us all to dinner, so...
你准备好了就叫上我
I'm ready whenever you are.
他有的只是个主意
All he had was an idea.
可那是很重要的一部分
Well, that is an important part.
拜托!
Oh, please!
我整天满脑子的主意
I have ideas all day long.
颠覆海洋世界 让海豚玩耍人
Reverse SeaWorld where dolphins are allowed to pet people.
在中号和大号间加个新尺码 叫"杏号"
A new clothing size between medium and large called Marge.
以矮人"喷嚏精"的视角重讲"白雪公主"的故事
Snow White retold from the point of view of Sneezy.
为什么"万事通"不给他开点药?
Why won't Doc prescribe him something?
这下能知道了
We finally find out.
但Leonard主意很棒
But Leonard's idea was good.
行 那就"爱生气"... 他对什么那么生气?
Fine. Then Grumpy... what's he so grumpy about?
或许是因为他女朋友不挺他
Maybe his girlfriend won't take his side.
主意是我想到的!
I'm the one who thought of it!
他不也做了许多研究吗?
Well, didn't he do a lot of the work?
但他让人们将错就错得以为
But now he's happy to let people think
一切都是他的杰作
he's responsible for everything.
所以补偿你一架iPad操控的直升机啊!
And that's why you get an iPad helicopter!
比他更享有盛誉 是我的错吗?
Is it my fault I have a much bigger reputation than he does?
不是你的错
It's not your fault.
按字母排 论文上我名字靠前
Is it my fault that my name came first
是我的错吗?
on the paper alphabetically?
不是你的错
Not your fault.
记者引用我为首席科学家
Is it my fault that when the reporter cited me
而我没有指正 是我的错吗?
as the lead scientist I didn't correct him?
嘿 看那只可爱的小鸟
Hey, look at that pretty bird.
他总想成为焦点
He always needs all the attention.
真像个婴儿
He's such a baby.
我知道 我知道
I know, I know.
我发誓 他休想玩我的直升机
I swear, he is never ever playing with my helicopter.
好的 我先热一些食物
Okay, I'll start heating some of this stuff up.
谢谢
Thanks.
天啊
Oh, man.
这是我高中毕业舞会上戴的胸花...
This is the boutonniere from my high school prom...
我成人礼时留的一片蛋糕
a piece of cake from my Bar Mitzvah.
她有丢掉什么吗?
Did she throw anything away?
没有
No.
要是找到我的包皮 我就自杀
If I find my foreskin, I'm gonna kill myself.
好了 这里有 呃
Okay, so we've got, um,
三块牛胸肉 四个烘肉卷 一份千层饼
three briskets, four meatloafs, one lasagna...
不 那是烤面条
No, that's Noodle Kugel.
一份犹太千层饼...
One Jewish lasagna...
两个磅饼 每个约重八磅
two pound cakes that are about eight pounds each,
还有一大罐素球汤
and one giant container of Matzah ball soup.
老妈一直备在手头
Ma always kept it on hand,
就怕我生病
in case I got sick.
她觉得她的料理包治百病
She thought she could cure anything with her cooking.
甚至是那次我食物中毒
Even the time I got food poisoning.
吃她的料理吃的
From her cooking.
你还好吧?
You okay?
嗯 我很好
Yeah, I'm okay.
我们开始吧
Let's get started.
好的
You got it.
我永远跟她说不上话了
I'm never gonna talk to her again.
要别让大家过来吗?
Should we tell everyone not to come?
不 我想这么做
No. I want to do this.
好吧 你能撑住的话 我也会坚持的
Okay. Well, I'll keep it together if you can.
好的
Okay.
可我承诺不了!
I'm not making any promises!
你们能来真好
Glad you guys could make it.
当然
Of course.
哇哦 这里看起来真漂亮
Wow, it looks really pretty in here.
是啊 原来用上半打烛台真能营造氛围
Yeah, turns out half a dozen menorahs really sets a mood.
呃 Stuart 要是Howard卖了这栋房子
So, Stuart, have you thought about
你有想过怎么办吗?
what you'd do if Howard sells the house?
现在氛围没了
And there goes the mood.
嗨 哈喽
Hi. Hello.
噢 我得说向Leonard说一个特别的你好
Oh, and a special hello to Leonard,
他必须被提到名字
who needs to be mentioned by name.
真不做作
Subtle.
你还是被提到了 对吗?
But you got it, right?
嗨 各位
Hey, guys.
嗨 哈喽
Hey. Hi. Hello.
我只是想告诉大家
I just want everyone to know,
呃 今晚并不是一个悲伤的场合
uh, tonight's not a sad occasion.
嗯 我们只想吃那种晚餐
Yeah, we just want to have the kind of dinner
那种和以前一样的晚餐
that we've all had here so many times before.
有好的事物 好的朋友 有时吃到半夜
Good food, good friends, and sometime around midnight,
胃痛得让你们一心想死
heartburn that makes you pray for death.
你需要人帮厨吗?
Do you need any help in the kitchen?
不用 有我们就够了 你们随意
No, we got it. You guys make yourselves comfortable.
你们两个 我们今天是为了Howard而来 好吗?
All right, hey, you two, we're here for Howard right now, okay?
对 表现得像话一点
Yes, so please behave yourselves.
好 当然
Fine. Of course.
我听说你们俩 呃 一起写了篇论文
So I heard you two, uh, wrote a paper together.
这事怎么样了?
How's that going?
太好吃了
This food is amazing.
呃 就是没有蔬菜
Mm, and not a vegetable in sight.
你错了哦
That's not true.
我们这里有番茄
We've got tomatoes right here.
这么些聪明人围坐在一张充满烛光的桌子旁
All these bright people sitting around a table by candlelight.
仿佛我们在办18世纪的法国沙龙一样
Feels like we could be an 18th century French salon.
一点不错
Indeed.
Penny 沙龙就是
Penny, a salon is a gathering
文化人聚集起来 谈一天的趣事
where intellectuals entertained each other
用闪耀着智慧光芒的谈话相互娱乐
with sparkling conversations about issues of the day.
噢 那就像"视野"一样
Oh, so it's like "The View".
Sheldon "视野"是一个由女人主持的日播脱口秀
Sheldon, The View is a daytime talk show hosted by women.
噢 我知道了
Oh, I'm aware.
里面有Whoopi Goldberg
It features Whoopi Goldberg.
她在"星际迷航:下一代"里扮演Guinan
She played Guinan on "Star Trek: Next Gen".
Penny 下一代指的是星际迷航...
Penny, Next Gen refers to Star Trek...
闭嘴
Shut up.
我想来提议一个沙龙话题
I would like to propose a salon topic.
哦 那太好了 Rajesh
Ooh, please do, Rajesh.
在"饥饿游戏"里 队长是一个女人
The lead in "The Hunger Games" is a woman.
漫威让一个女人来当"Tor"
Marvel has made "Tor" a female.
等等 谁是"Tor"?
Wait, who's Tor?
就是 索 雷神啊(其实是索尔)
You know, Tor, the God of "Tunder".
如我所说 这是不是表明了
As I was saying, is this a sign
我们的社会正在走向两性平等呢?
that our society is approaching gender equality?
现在确实有很多女人在看漫画书了啊
Certainly a lot more women are reading comic books now.
是的
It's true.
我店里的厕所马桶都得装座垫了
At the store, I had to put a seat on the toilet.
除非女索尔生个孩子
We won't know if there's equality
复仇者也不在意工作的时候她在一旁挤奶
until female Thor has a baby
否则我们也不知道是不是平等
and the Avengers are cool with her pumping breast milk at work.
我就想知道那个孩子是不是
I wonder if only a baby who is worthy
也得有本事才能吃女索尔的奶(雷神之锤梗)
can suckle at the bosom of Thor.
好吧 新的话题
Okay, new salon topic.
沙龙... 是很久前就有的蠢东西
Salons... dumb thing from a long time ago
还是本来有趣却因谈超级英雄而变得很蠢?
or interesting thing made dumb by talking about superheroes?
讨论吧
Discuss.
我不觉得话题有什么重要的
I don't believe it matters what the topic is.
沙龙里最重要的是
What's crucial for a salon
我们用一种高端和充满洞察力的方式
is that we conduct the discussion
进行讨论
in an elevated and insightful way.
重要的是执行
It's all about the execution.
当然重要的是执行而不是灵感
Of course you'd focus on that rather than the inspiration.
呃 新话题
Uh, new salon topic.
灵感与执行 哪个更重要?
What's more important, an idea or its execution?
噢 这个好玩
Oh, that's fun.
对啊 这话题对你多合适 Leonard
Yeah, good for you, Leonard.
这真是一个可爱的小概念
That's a lovely little notion.
就好像是
Kind of like,
"要是能和我芝加哥的叔叔通电话就好了"
"I wish I could talk to my uncle in Chicago."
对啊 靠边站 哥发明了电话
Yeah, now stand back while I invent the telephone.
"哈喽? 呃 等等"
"Hello? Oh, hold on."
Leonard 是你叔叔
Leonard, it's your uncle.
他说你刚刚被讽刺傻了
He says you just got burned.
Sheldon啊
Sheldon.
- 你们啊  - 不 没事
- You guys.  - No, it's okay.
我们都是成年人 正在进行一场智慧的讨论
We're all adults trying to have an intelligent discussion.
起码我是
At least I am.
Howard 你怎么看
Howard, what do you think?
好吧 我想作为一个工程师 我倾向于执行
Well, I guess, as an engineer, I lean towards execution.
我每天都
I spend my days
努力的去
trying to take
把想法变成现实
ideas and make them real.
说得好 伙计
Well said, old chap.
我以为演说家都死完了 结果今天我们这儿又出来一个
I thought eloquence had died, here it stands before us.
从今天开始 就是"葛底斯堡的演说"
Starting today, it'll go: "Gettysburg Address,
"我有一个梦想" 还有你刚才说的
"I have a dream" and what you just said.
噢 现在他是个天才了?
Oh, now he's a genius?
以前你只取笑他和工程学而已
All you ever do is make fun of him and engineering.
拜托 Leonard 他母亲刚刚去世
Leonard, please. His mother just died.
你太荒唐了
You're being ridiculous.
对 你也是
Yeah, so are you.
各位 如果你想听人哔哔的话
Guys, if I wanted to hear people be bitchy,
我就去我真正的剪头沙龙了
I'd go to my real salon.
Leonard 很多人可能有过这一想法
Leonard, lots of people could've had that idea,
但很少有人可以
but very few people could've
像我一样把数学公式理清
worked out the math the way I did.
但是很多人没有这想法
Lots of people also didn't have that idea,
这世界上所有人都没有 除了我
like everyone in the entire world except for me.
噢 好吧 很显然Leonard认为
Oh, well, apparently Leonard thinks
他比全世界所有人都厉害
he's better than everyone in the whole world,
也包括那些
including those
为我们自由而战的人
fighting for our freedom.
好吧 我不了解你
Yeah, well, I don't know about you,
但我支持我们派驻海外的战士
but I support our boys overseas.
还有女战士
And girls.
嘿 你已经毁了索尔 歇一会吧
Hey, you already ruined Thor, give it a rest.
所以我应该赞同你
So I'm just supposed to be okay
独占所有的荣誉是吗?!
with you hogging all the credit?!
我什么都没占
I didn't hog anything.
不像你 还有带葡萄干的的奇怪烤面条
Unlike you and that weird lasagna with raisins in it.
你想要这个?
You want some of this?
- 我给你来点  - 嘿!
- I'll give you some.  - Hey!
Sheldon Leonard 给我出去 现在!
Sheldon, Leonard, living room, right now!
她先说了我的名字 你一定受不了吧
She said my name first, that must kill you.
我不知道你们想干什么
I don't know what you think you're doing,
但这是一个对我丈夫而言很重要的时刻
but this is a very difficult time for my husband!
我们正在吃他妈妈留下的最后食物
We're eating the last food his mother ever made,
你们竟然像孩子一样把它们互相乱扔?!
and you were gonna throw it at each other like children?!
我不管你们在吵什么 先放一边
Whatever it is you're fighting about, put it aside,
回去做个Howard的好朋友
go back in there and be a good friend to Howard
否则你们就都别想吃甜点了!
or there's no dessert for either of you!
跟你讲话的时候看着我!
Look at me when I'm talking to you!
不要以为...
And don't think...
你们有没有注意到 有时Bernadette说话像我妈妈一样?
You guys ever notice sometimes Bernadette sounds like my mom?
- 没听见  - 一点儿不像
- I don't hear it.  - No, not at all.
我觉得我这辈子都没吃过这么多东西
I don't think I've eaten that much in my entire life.
怪不得我祖先在沙漠里走了40年
It's why my people wandered the desert for 40 years.
走了这么久才消了食
Took that long to walk it off.
你看 Penny 以色列人在沙漠里...
You see, Penny, the Israelites were in the desert...
闭嘴!
Shut up!
太好了你们终于吵完了
So glad you two are done fighting.
现在 我只是努力的不在打嗝时吐出来
Right now, I'm just trying to burp without throwing up.
"今日物理"提到那篇论文了
"Physics Today" mentioned the paper.
他们说什么
What'd they say?
管那个干什么? 他们提到Leonard?
Who cares? Did they mention Leonard?
他们提到了
They did.
太好了
Yay.
好消息 我找到了更多的咀嚼片
Good news, I found more Tums.
太好了!
Yay!